

Susanna Peretti

Email: susa.peretti@gmail.com Email: s.peretti@campus.uniurb.it

Website: https://github.com/SusaPrt

Gender: Female **Date of birth:** 19 May 1999 **Nationality:** Italian

ABOUT ME

Hi, I'm Susanna! I earned a Bachelor's degree in Applied Computer Science from the University of Urbino, where I developed skills in software engineering and verification, operating systems, databases and signal processing, as well as programming languages belonging to different paradigms. Currently, I am enrolled in the Master's degree program in Computer Science and Digital Innovation at the same university while pursuing a research scholarship.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[16 Oct 2023 – Current]

Research scholarship

IoT and ML solutions for engagement and recognition of semantic activities on an urban scale

University of Urbino 'Carlo Bo'

The project aims to develop IoT solutions using shallow and deep learning for semantic activity recognition. It focuses on analyzing signals from wearable devices, selecting relevant features, and assessing computational efficiency.

[1 Feb 2023 - 31 Jul 2023] Internship

Alternative signal processing tools to machine learning

University of Urbino 'Carlo Bo'

The internship involves the analysis and utilization of various methods of digital signal processing (DSP) for human activity recognition using machine learning algorithms. The goal is to explore different DSP techniques to extract and analyze relevant features from signals coming from wearable sensors that record human body movements.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[2 Oct 2023 – Current]

Master's Degree in Computer Science and Digital Innovation

University of Urbino 'Carlo Bo'

Curriculum: Artificial intelligence

[28 Sep 2020 – 21 Sep 2023]

Bachelor's Degree in Applied Computer Science

University of Urbino 'Carlo Bo'

Final grade: 108 | Thesis: Impact of feature selection on pattern identification in handwashing (experimental)

Curriculum: Digital Information Processing

[10 Sep 2013 – 20 Jul 2018] **Scientific maturity**

Institute of Higher Education L. da Penne - M. dei Fiori

CONFERENCES AND SEM-INARS

[11 Mar 2024 – 15 Mar 2024]

22nd International Conference on Pervasive Computing and Communications (PerCom 2024) Biarritz (FR)

PUBLICATIONS

[2024]

Complexity-aware Features Selection for Wrist-worn Human Activity Recognition

Reference: Susanna Peretti, Chiara Contoli, Emanuele Lattanzi

Presented at PeRConAI 2024: 3rd International Workshop on Pervasive and Resource-Constrained Artificial Intelligence, Biarrizt (FR)

Semantic Template Recognition of Human Activities in Wearable Sensor Data Using Siamese

[2024] **Network**

Reference: E. Lattanzi, C. Contoli, L.Calisti, G. Di Fabrizio, N. Kania, S.Peretti

An Experimental Study on the Energy Efficiency of Features Selection for Human Activity

[2024] Recognition with wrist-worn Devices

Reference: Susanna Peretti, Chiara Contoli, Emanuele Lattanzi

Presented at the 9th International Workshop on Sensor-Based Activity Recognition and Artificial Intelligence (iWoar 2024), Potsdam (GE)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Italian

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

VOLUNTEERING

[Sep 2013 – Jun 2020]

Red Cross Volunteer

I have actively participated in the planning and organization of events and activities for the community. Additionally, I have created multimedia content such as posters and videos for the social media pages of the local Penne Committee and the regional Abruzzo Committee.

COLLABORATIONS

[1 Apr 2022 – Current]

Audio technician

I collaborate as an audio technician for an amateur sports association of artistic roller skating called 'Roller Up'. My responsibilities include setting up computers, mixers, and speakers, as well as managing music during events. Additionally, I also serve as a photographer during athletes' competitions and performances.

I authorize the processing of my personal data included in my CV in accordance with Article 13 of Legislative Decree No. 196/2003 of June 30, 2003 - 'Code regarding the protection of personal data' and Article 13 of GDPR 679/16 - 'General Data Protection Regulation'.

Urbino, Dec 2024